## JYOTSNA CHUTIA

#### IMPLEMENTATION MANAGER

+91-8335816000

chetiajyotsna30@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jyotsna-chetia-101243106/

# **SKILLS**

- PKI
- MFT
- Data Security
- Certificate Lifecycle Management
- UNIX
- Cryptography
- Problem solving
- Project Management Tools
- Excellent Communication skills
- Strong ability to prioritize and manage multiple projects simultaneously

### **PROFILE**

Having 8 years of experience, well-fortified in PKI concepts, patterns and practices, managed file transfer, cryptographic concepts - symmetric/asymmetric cryptography, secure hash, digital signatures with current role as Implementation Manager. Responsible for managing Client Implementation/Technical Integration/Solution delivery as well as Servicing of Cash Management solutions for Global Banking and Corporate customer.

Having excellent communication and strong analytical skills. A committed team player, fast learner, and detail oriented.

## EXPERIENCE

#### IMPLEMENTATION MANAGER

HDFC Bank, Mumbai

2019 - Present

- Working as a PKI admin for Digicert (CA), responsible for certificate lifecycle management
- Issuance of certificate based on end user requirements like Trusted cert, digital signature/encryption certs, code signing certs, internal/private certificates
- Design, implement and maintain the PKI environment (Root CA, Subordinate Cas, OCSP, Revocation)
- Managing Digital certificates, cryptographic keys, key stores, trust stores and other cryptographic services.
- Configuration of Network Firewall changes depending on client requirements to establish secure connections
- Creation of certificates, PGP and SSH keys, exchange with the clients and installation of keys and certificates at the server.
- Worked on implementing channel establishments across different platforms.
- Session level Security using secure network protocols SFTP, FTP-SSL.
- Understanding of cryptographic concepts: symmetric/asymmetric cryptography, secure hash, digital signatures.

#### **ANALYST**

Deutsche Bank, Mumbai

2016 - 2019

- Worked on setting up of secure transmission channel between the Bank and Client via HTTPS, SFTP, FTPS, AS2 protocols for seamless delivery of payment & transaction files.
- Installation of new certs and renewal activity.

## **EDUCATION**

### **Bachelors of Computer Application**

Veer Bahadur Purvanchal University

2008-2011

## **Masters of Computer Application**

**Amity University** 

2011-2014

- Configuration of inhouse DB-Direct Connect (DBDC) setup, a global file transfer platform developed by Deutsche Bank which provides bi-directional transfer of data file from Customer's host system to DB's processing system.
- Intensively worked on DB Direct Internet (DBDI) one of the in-house Frontend applications for payment and accounting module providing electronic banking service for testing various technical functionalities and transaction banking facilities.

#### **PROJECT ENGINEER**

### Wipro Technologies, Kolkata

2014 - 2016

- Worked on configuration of webMethods Broker, Adapters and migrating integrations from one environment to another.
- Have Installed and updated AS2 certificates in Trading Networks and tested AS2 connectivity with partners.
- Extensively used Deployer tool to migrate webMethods
- components from one environment to other and solved problems related deploying.
- Worked on configuration of Partner profiles, External ID's, Processing rules, Trading Partner Agreements in Trading Networks.